# AKASH SINGH

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



+91 6394636465



mr.singhaksh@gmail.com



Jaunpur, U.P.



theakashsingh



theakashsingh

## **EDUCATION**

V.B.S.P. UNIVERSITY

Bachelor Of Technology In Information Technology 2016 - 2020

## SKILLS

React.js JavaScript TypeScript Redux HTML CSS SASS Tailwind Node.is

### **PROFILE**

I am a front-end developer with over two years of experience in React. I have focused on user-centred design, accessibility, and responsive principles to create high-quality, visually appealing websites. My passion for innovation drives my commitment to continuous skill development, while my collaborative approach ensures successful project outcomes.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Humane club | Oct, 2021 - July 2023

- View Dashboard: Created React UI components (e.g., dropdowns, sliders, filters) for a polished Humane Dashboard, with redux managing state.
- Dynamic Forms and Data Displays: Developed dynamic React forms and data displays, integrating seamlessly into the Humane Dashboard, while Redux handled state.
- Nudge Bot Chatbot & Plugin Integration: Developed a versatile Nudge Bot chatbot with 50+ features. I have integrated it as a plugin, offering chat history, analytics, and customization for 100+ clients.
- Dynamic Table of Contents Plugin: Designed a React-based plugin that auto-generated content lists for blog posts, enhanced navigation, and managed with React/redux.
- Data Synchronization with Rest API: Integrated Data Wrapper for one-click data sync, including complex calculations. Redux.js managed real-time monitoring and data integrity, all within the browser.

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

PAPERBRIDGE SOLUTIONS PRIVATE LIMITED | Aug 2023 -Present

- Content Management Dashboard: Develop a React-based dashboard for managing articles, tracking revisions, scheduling publications, and real-time collaboration with RBAC, Redux for state management, drag-and-drop functionality, and analytics integration.
- Interactive Content Visualization Tool: Create a React tool for visualizing content performance using dynamic charts ( Chart.js), customizable filters, and exportable reports.